Addison Emery Verrill Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
- Correspondence, 1864-1926; Series I
  - Fred Mather Correspondence. Correspondence from F. Mather to A.E. Verrill., 1885; 001247
    - Fred Mather Correspondence. A letter from F. Mather to S.F. Baird, forwarded to A.E. Verrill. In the letter on Forest & Stream letter head, Mather talks about a drainage pipe clogged with some sort of Tunicates. Also in the pipe were Mya, tube worms, Nereis, Mytilus, oysters, jingle shells and small anenomes. A Verrill not on the letter reads "Cynthia partita?", 08 Aug 1885; 001248
  - Frederick Habershaw Correspondence. Correspondence from F. Habershaw to A.E. Verrill., 1878; 001270
    - Frederick Habershaw Correspondence. A letter from F. Habershaw informing Verrill of a colleague, John H. Mortimer who will be returning to New York soon and has a collection of Scyphozoa he wishes for Verrill to see., 26 Jan 1878; 001271
  - Frederick J.V. Skiff Correspondence. Correspondence from F.J.V. Skiff to A.E. Verrill., 1907; 001597
    - Frederick J.V. Skiff Correspondence. A letter from F.J.V. Skiff to A.E. Verrill informing him he is enclosing a list of material that will be sent., 20 Aug 1907; 001598
  - Frederick William True Correspondence. Correspondence from F.W. True to A.E. Verrill., 1899; 001688
    - Frederick William True Correspondence. A letter from F.W. True to A.E. Verrill informing Verrill that at the request of J.E. Benedict he is sending the last 2 Yale specimens of Sesarma back to Verrill., 17 Nov 1899; 001689
  - George Brown Goode Correspondence. Correspondence from G.B. Goode to A.E. Verrill., 1877; 001228
    - George Brown Goode Correspondence. A letter from G.B. Goode to A.E. Verrill informing him he will be sending corals and Ophiuroidea and discusses a proposal for a series of memoirs on the Natural History of Bermuda. He encloses a list of 14 proposed memoirs and suggested authors., 17 Jun 1877; 001229
    - George Brown Goode Correspondence. A letter from G.B. Goode to A.E. Verrill informing him he has sent 5 parcels of specimens from Bermuda, including Siderastraea, Eunice, Plexaura, Octopoda, Strombus, Astrangia and Crustacea., 19 Jun 1877; 001230
  - George Frederick Matthew Correspondence. Correspondence from G.F. Matthew to A.E. Verrill., 1868; 001415
    - George Frederick Matthew Correspondence. A letter from G.F. Matthew informing Verrill he is sending his Cuba collection, mostly fossil. See YPM Acc. No. 21. See Invoice Ledger., 07 Jan 1868; 001416
  - George Henry Horn Correspondence. Correspondence from G.H. Horn to A.E. Verrill., 001426
    - George Henry Horn Correspondence. A letter from G.H. Horn with a list of identified Coleoptera apparently sent to him by Verrill. A note in Verrill's hand on the letter reads "Salt water & shore beetles." See Invoice Ledger., 001427
  - George M. Totten Correspondence. Correspondence from G.M. Totten to A.E. Verrill., 1881; 001298
    - George M. Totten Correspondence. A letter from G.M. Totten informing Verrill he has sent the box of birds collected by Guillermo Nanne from Guatemala., 30 Dec 1881; 001299
  - George Perkins Merrill Correspondence. Correspondence from G.P. Perkins to A.E. Verrill., 1900; 001682
    - George Perkins Merrill Correspondence. A letter from G.P Perkins, informing Verrill that at the request of R. Rathbun, he is sending 3 duplicate invoices of the loans returned by Verrill to the USNM. He regrest the delay to the absence of W.H. Dall., 29 Mar 1900; 001683
  - Gustaf Lindstrom Correspondence. Correspondence from G. Lindstrom to A.E. Verrill., 1872; 001128
    - Gustaf Lindstrom Correspondence. Transcribed copy of a letter from G. Lindstrom to A.E. Verrill inforimg him he is sending him papers on fossil Corals and requesting copies of Verrill's papers on Radiata. Also discussing coral classification. See Related Object in Assocations tab., 30 Oct 1872; 001140
  - H. Wheeler Correspondence. Correspondence from H. Wheeler to A.E. Verrill., 1865; 001255
    - H. Wheeler Correspondence. A letter from H. Wheeler of Davenport, Iowa to J.D. Dana, forwarded to A.E. Verrill. He informs Dana he is sending a package of minerals and a fossil coral. The minerals are from various localities listed, and the coral from Panama. A Verrill note on the letter reads "Fossil Coral Panama.", 17 May 1865; 001256
  - H.S. Hoyt Correspondence. Correspondence from H.S. Hoyt to A.E. Verrill., 1899; 001677
    - H.S. Hoyt Correspondence. A letter from H.S. Hoyt to A.E. Verrill informing him he is sending a female antelope head from Colorado., 07 Jul 1899; 001678
  - H.T. Woodman Correspondence. Correspondence from H.T. Woodman to A.E. Verrill., 1886-1887; 001221
    - H.T. Woodman Correspondence. A letter from H.T. Woodman to A.E. Verrill thanking him for his help and telling him of some East Indian corals he has that he thinks Verrill would be interested in., 08 Aug 1887; 001232
    - H.T. Woodman Correspondence. A letter from H.T. Woodman to A.E. Verrill asking him for help in identifying corals. He offers to send them, and future interesting specimens, asking only for the freight to be paid and to be given the appropriate credit if they should turn out to be new., 08 Jun 1886; 001231
    - H.T. Woodman Correspondence. A letter from H.T. Woodman to A.E. Verrill informing him he has sent a few shells collected some 15 years prior from Tampa Bay, Florida. He describeds the habits of the snails and asks Verrill to identify them., 13 Jun 1887; 001222
  - H.W. Beckwith Correspondence. Correspondence from H.W. Beckwith to A.E. Verrill., 1891; 001282
    - H.W. Beckwith Correspondence. A letter from H.W. Beckwith informing Verrill he is sending humming bird eggs collected from near his house in Eat Lyme, Connecticut., 30 Mar 1891; 001283
  - Henry Augustus Pilsbry Correspondence. Correspondence from H.A. Pilsbry to A.E. Verrill., 1900; 001182
    - Henry Augustus Pilsbry Correspondence. A letter and list form H.A. Pilsbry to A.E. Verrill. The letter is telling Verrill he is returning the Bermuda terrestrial snails with the identifications on an enclosed list and discussing a paper on the subject that he is writing., 01 Nov 1900; 001183
  - Henry Augustus Ward Correspondence. Correspondence from H.A. Ward to A.E. Verrill., 1887-1892; 001176
    - Henry Augustus Ward Correspondence. Letters from H.A. Ward to A.E. Verrill in regards to sales and exchanges of specimens. Also includes lists of various specimens. Letters and lists are bundled together., 20 Sep 1887 - 10 Feb 1892; 001177
  - Henry Hemphill Correspondence. Correspondence from H. Hemphill to A.E. Verrill., 1875; 001146
    - Henry Hemphill Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from H. Hemphill to A.E. Verrill telling him he has on hand several species of Echinodermata, Porifera, Anthozoa, etc. he wishes to have named. See Related Object in Associations tab., 19 May 1875; 001147
  - Henry Kessler Correspondence. Correspondence from H. Kessler to A.E. Verrill., 1889; 001294
    - Henry Kessler Correspondence. A letter from H. Kessler to O.C. Marsh apparently forwarded to Verrill. Kessler asks for an indentification of an animal he had never seen before in the area of Wyoming he was in. A Verrill note on the letter says "Big Cricket.", 27 Aug 1889; 001295
  - Henry Weatherbee Henshaw Correspondence. Correspondence from H.W. Henshaw to A.E. Verrill., 1877; 001373
    - Henry Weatherbee Henshaw Correspondence. A letter from H.W. Henshaw informing Verrill he is sending "leeches" taken from the gut of a Podiceps auritus californicus from Lake Tahoe. See Invoice Ledger., 24 Mar 1877; 001374
  - Herbert C. Reed Correspondence. Correspondence from H.C. Reed to A.E. Verrill., 1900; 001690
    - Herbert C. Reed Correspondence. A letter from H.C Reed to Verrill informing him he is sending a worm specimen found in log of wood from Argentina that he had imprted for his company., 25 Jan 1900; 001691
  - Horace Francis Carpenter Correspondence. Correspondence from H.F. Carpenter to A.E. Verrill., 1872; 001218
    - Horace Francis Carpenter Correspondence. A letter from H.F. Carpenter to J.D. Dana, and forwarded to A.E. Verrill. The letter says 2 specimens of a new species of shell from Rhode Island have been sent. He states the shells were described in a series of papers on the Conchology of Rhode Island, printed in the Central Falls, RI Weekly Visitor, a copy of which containing the description he has sent., 13 Apr 1872; 001219
    - Horace Francis Carpenter Correspondence. A letter from H.F. Carpenter to A.E. Verrill informing him J.D. Dana suggested he contact Verrill. He assures Verrill the shells previously sent are a new species and lists a few conchologists he sent the shells to. Some of which disagreed with him. He encloses more of the shells and gives the specific locality., 16 Aug 1872; 001220
  - Identification Requests. Correspondence with requests for specimen identification., 1864-1926; 001117
    - Identification Requests. 2 letters from the Department of Docks, Pier "A," Foot of Battery Place, N.R. to A.E. Verrill. The first letter, informing him a worm eaten specimen of wharf pile is being sent to him. The second letter contains information is regards to specific locallity, depth and tide conditions of the pile. On the second letter Verrill wrote at the top "Teredo bored wood (piles)", 17 Jan 1894; 001118
    - Identification Requests. A transcribed copy of a letter from O.M. Baker, Webster's International Dictionary to A.E. Verrill asking him to review Funk & Wangall's Standard Dictionary and comment on a page of birds that O.M. Bakers believes are colored wrong. See Related Object in Associations tab., 001149
  - J. Matthew Jones Correspondence. Correspondence from J.M. Jones to A.E. Verrill., 1877; 001260
    - J. Matthew Jones Correspondence. A post card from J.M. Jones to A.E. Verrill. It is mostly illegible as it has been written over, possibly discussing an exchange., 09 Nov 1877; 001261
  - J.H. Sternbergh Correspondence. Correspondence from J.H. Sternbergh to A.E. Verrill., 1867; 001395
    - J.H. Sternbergh Correspondence. A letter from J.H. Sternbergh acknowledging Verrill's receipt of the tapir (See YPMZ Acc. No. 257) as well as describing some bees he had sent through F.H. Bradley. See Invoice Ledger., 31 May 1867; 001396
  - James Everhard Benedict Correspondence. Correspondence from J.E. Benedict to A.E. Verrill., 1895; 001106
    - James Everhard Benedict Correspondence. A letter from J.E. benedict to A.E. Verrill that discusses a loan of Asteroidea to Verril. Specifically Mediaster aequalis, Porania grandis, and Solaster. Also discussed is the cataloging of Porifera., 07 Feb 1895; 001107
  - James M. Whiton Correspondence. Correspondence from J.M. Whiton to A.E. Verrill., 1868; 001310
    - James M. Whiton Correspondence. A letter from J.M. Whiton to G.J. Brush, apparently forwarded to Verrill. The letter discusses the possible donation of an entomology collection by a friend of his, a Mr. Harvey J, Rich. He also talks about Mr. Rich being a possible donor to the Sheffield Scientific School., 16 Nov 1868; 001311
  - James Orton Correspondence. Correspondence from J. Orton to A.E. Verrill., 1868-1870; 001131
    - James Orton Correspondence. A letter from J. Orton to A.E. Verrill informing him he has shipped a can of alcoholic specimens from the West Coast of South America. Included are Crustacea and fishes., 07 Oct 1868; 001225
    - James Orton Correspondence. A letter from J. Orton that encloses a list of Reptilia specimens identified by E.D. Cope from the Upper Amazon. He asks Verrill if ther are of interest to him, he would be happy to send the specimens., 11 Mar 1870; 001288
    - James Orton Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from J. Orton to A.E. Verrill telling Verrill the Upper Amazon Reptiles he sent were a present, not and exchange. But requests shells and corals if available. See Related Object in Associations tab., 19 Mar 1870; 001150
  - Joel Asaph Allen Correspondence. Correspondence from J.A. Allen to A.E. Verrill., 1891 - 1892; 001286
    - Joel Asaph Allen Correspondence. 3 letters from J.A. Allen discussing the identification of birds sent to him from Verrill and Verrill's sons. Some of the birds are from Dominica., 19 Jun 1891 - 13 May 1892; 001287
  - John G. Anthony Correspondence. Correspondence from J.G. Anthony to A.E. Verrill., 1868-1869; 001193
    - John G. Anthony Correspondence. A letter from J.G. Anthony thanking A.E. Verrill for the Modiolaria Verrill had sent. He laos asks Verrill what he would like in return., 03 Nov 1869; 001194
    - John G. Anthony Correspondence. A letter from J.G. Anthony informing Verrill he is sending the shells from Brazil. He encloses a list of the specimens. See Invoice Ledger., 11 Dec 1868; 001401
    - John G. Anthony Correspondence. A letter from J.G. Anthony giving the identification of some shells Verrill had sent him. See Invoice Ledger., 11 Jun 1869; 001403
    - John G. Anthony Correspondence. A list of specimens (mollusca) returned to Yale College. See Invoice Ledger., 001402
  - John Green Brady Correspondence. Correspondence from J.G. Brady to A.E. Verrill., 1880; 001241
    - John Green Brady Correspondence. A letter from J.G. Brady to O.C. Marsh, forwarded to A.E. Verrill. It informs he is sending a specimen from Sitka, Alaska, collected at 45 fathoms by a halibut fishing vessel,. A Verrill note on the letter reads Verrilliana Blakei., 13 Sep 1880; 001242
  - John P. Terry Correspondence. Corresppondence from J.P. Terry to A.E. Verrill., 1887 - 1892; 001291
    - John P. Terry Correspondence. 3 letters from J.P. Terry. In each letter he is sending a specimen (arachnid) for Verrill's identification. On the second letter there is a Verrill note that reads "Salfuga (figd)"., 11 Oct 1887 - 13 Apr 1892; 001292
  - John Strong Newberry Correspondence. Correspondence from J.S. Newberry to A.E. Verrill., 001595
    - John Strong Newberry Correspondence. A letter from J.S. Newberry asking Verrill to identify a sponge if possible., 001596
  - John Winters Jones Correspondence. Correspondence from J.W. Jones to A.E. Verrill., 1870; 001541
    - John Winters Jones Correspondence. A letter from J.W. Jones informing Verrill he is sending the "Catalogue of Lithophytes" in behalf of the British Museum., 18 Oct 1870; 001542
  - Joseph Albert Lintner Correspondence. Correspondence from J.A. Lintner to A.E. Verrill., 1879; 001266
    - Joseph Albert Lintner Correspondence. A letter from J.A. Lintner asking Verrill to identify a parasite that was removed from the "lower stomach" of a lamb., 27 Oct 1879; 001267
  - Joseph Frederick Whiteaves Correspondence. Correspondence from J.F. Whiteaves to A.E. Verrill., 1880 - 1897; 001233
    - Joseph Frederick Whiteaves Correspondence. A letter from J.F. Whiteaves thanking Verrill for his notes on the Queen Charlotte Island Echinodermata, Anthozoa, etc. He says he will send Verrill a proof of his paper and asks for any alterations and additions., 01 Mar 1880; 001236
    - Joseph Frederick Whiteaves Correspondence. A letter from J.F. Whiteaves asking Verrill to describe the Archaster and the 2 species of Solaster he had previously sent. He informs Verrill to please hold off sending collections until they have had time to settle into the new museum in Ottawa. He also includes a list of desired west coast shells., 04 Mar 1880; 001237
    - Joseph Frederick Whiteaves Correspondence. A letter from J.F. Whiteaves asking A.E. Verrill if had time to look at the Queen Charlotte Asteroidea he had sent him the prior summer. Whiteaves is finishing up a report and is anxious to get it off his hands. He also asks Verrill if has finished with the Gulf of Saint Lawrence shells he had sent, as Jeffreys has written requesting to see them., 09 Feb 1880; 001234
    - Joseph Frederick Whiteaves Correspondence. A letter from J.F. Whiteaves thanking Verrill for the information he had sent, apparently for a report by Dr. R. Bell. He says he would like to send him a series of Bela from the Gulf of Saint Lawrence sometime in the future and aks for a few specimens of Conella from the west coast. He also is sorry to hear of the death of Dr. Jeffreys., 26 Feb 1885; 001238
    - Joseph Frederick Whiteaves Correspondence. A letter from J.F. Whiteaves discussing Bela shells with Verrill and askign for the reutnr of previously loaned specimens., 27 Dec 1897; 001679
    - Joseph Frederick Whiteaves Correspondence. A letter from J.F. Whiteaves informing Verrill he is sending specimens of Echinodermata from the Queen Charlotte Islands and asking for help in identifications, some of which Verrill may keep. He asks for west coast shells and corals in return. He sent 2 examples of a small Echinus, two specimens of Solaster and a 5 rayed starfish. He says the Echinus may be kept., 27 Feb 1880; 001235
  - Joseph Willcox Correspondence. Correspondence from J. Willcox to A.E. Verrill., 1887; 001168
    - Joseph Willcox Correspondence. A letter from J. Willcox to A.E. Verrill thanking him for the box of shells Verrill sent in exchange., 03 Aug 1887; 001171
    - Joseph Willcox Correspondence. A letter from J. Willcox to A.E. Verrill informing him he has a shipment of Pliocene shells ready to be shipped in exchange for West Coast shells and other specimens. He enclosed a list of the Pliocene shells to be sent., 20 Jul 1887; 001169
    - Joseph Willcox Correspondence. A letter from J. Willcox to A.E. Verrill informing him he will ship Pliocene shells to the Peabody Museum, and giving Verrill instructions on where to ship the shells in exhange.., 27 Jul 1887; 001170
    - Joseph Willcox Correspondence. A postcard from J. Willcox to A.E. Verrill telling him where he can find a duplicate list of the specimens he had sent. Willcox says that when he sent the fossils he did not keep a list himself, but he had sent duplicates to Prof. Whitfield in New York. He tells Verrill if he needs to, he could get a duplicate from him., 28 Nov 1887; 001306
  - Loomis J. Campbell Correspondence. Correspondence from L.J. Campbell to A.E. Verrill., 1887; 001262
    - Loomis J. Campbell Correspondence. A ltter from L.J. Campbell to A.E. Verrill discussing the editing of the dictionary Verrill was helping prepare., 02 Jun 1887; 001263
  - Mary Jane Rathbun Correspondence. Correspondence from M.J. Rathbun to A.E. Verrill., 1897; 001680
    - Mary Jane Rathbun Correspondence. A letter from M.J. Rathbun informing Verrill she is sending back the collection of Sesarma she had borrwed. She is also sending Brazilian crabs for S.I. Smith collected by Hartt 1870 and duplicates from R. Rathbun 1875-1877. An Invoice of the Sesarma was enclosed, cataloged separately. See IZAR No. 1684, 29 Mar 1897; 001681
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. Miscellaneous correspondence. Letters from unknown people, etc., 1864-1926; 001152
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from "C. Kouser" [Spelling questionable] requestion Gorgonacea from Verrill for research purposes. As well as Asteroidea, Echinoidea and Holothuroidea. See Related Object in Associations tab., 17 Dec 1866; 001153
  - Moses Harvey Correspondence. Correspondence from M. Harvey to A.E. Verrill., 1876; 001172
    - Moses Harvey Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from M. Harvey to A.E. Verrill discussing a tape worm from a salmon in Newfoundland.. It also discusses the identity of a whale. Verrill wrote on envelope "Harvey, Tapeworm, etc., basking shark". See Related Object in Associations tab., 11 Oct 1876; 001143
  - Mrs. R.W. Summers Correspondence. Correspondence from Mrs. R.W. Summers to A.E. Verrill., 1885; 001274
    - Mrs. R.W. Summers Correspondence. A letter from Mrs. R.W. Summer informing Verrill she had sent him some specimens from San Luis Obispo, CA for indetification. She also encloses a list of duplicate specimens in her collection for possible exchange., 02 Sep 1885; 001275
  - Personal Correspondence. Personal correspondence to A.E. Verrill. Not related to his research., 1877; 001144
    - Personal Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from C. Semper to A.E. Verrill inquiring when he could find Verrill at home in the Last week of November or first week of December. See Related Object in Associations tab., 16 Nov 1877; 001145
  - Philip Herbert Carpenter Correspondence. Correspondence from P.H. Carpenter to A.E. Verrill., 1882; 001129
    - Philip Herbert Carpenter Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from P.H. Carpenter to A.E. Verrill discussing Crinoidea. He thanks Verrill for copies of his papers on the USFC dredging work. See Related Object in Associations tab., 13 Aug 1882; 001142
  - Philip Pearsall Carpenter Correspondence. Correspondence from P.P. Carpenter to A.E. Verrill., 1870; 001389
    - Philip Pearsall Carpenter Correspondence. A letter believed to be from P.P. Caprenter forwarding notes on shells from Dr. Dawson and the staff at the British Museum to A.E. Verrill. See Invoice Ledger., 05 Aug 1870; 001390
  - R. Ellsworth Call Correspondence. Correspondence from R.E. Call to A.E. Verrill., 1885; 001179
    - R. Ellsworth Call Correspondence. A letter from R.E. Call to A.E. Verrill telling him he is sending Verrill's share of the specimens collected during the "Tennessee shell trip" and thanking him for his contribution., 05 Oct 1885; 001181
    - R. Ellsworth Call Correspondence. A letter from R.E. Call to A.E. Verrill where he is sending Verrill a paper on the Unionids of the Mississippi Valey and box of specimens. He also asks Verrill to contribute expenses for an upcoming collection trip, for which he would send Verrill specimens from., 24 Jun 1885; 001180
  - Rev. Lewis Grout Correspondence. Correspondence from L. Grout to A.E. Verrill., 1887; 001214
    - Rev. Lewis Grout Correspondence. A letter from L. Grout inforimg A.E. Verrill he is sending him land shells from Natal and Zululand, South Africa for identification and as a donation if desired., 04 Jul 1887; 001215
  - Richard Rathbun Correspondence. Correspondence from R. Rathbun to A.E. Verrill., 1880-1884; 001109
    - Richard Rathbun Correspondence. 3 letters from R. Rathbun to A.E. Verrill discussing USFC collections., 23 Nov 1880 - 27 Oct 1881; 001110
  - Robert George Bell Correspondence. Correspondence from R.G. Bell to A.E. Verrill., 1883; 001189
    - Robert George Bell Correspondence. 4 letters from R.G. Bell to A.E. Verrill requestion papers on American shells and inquiriing about exchanges., 16 Apr 1883 - 03 Oct 1883; 001190
  - Robert Hungerford Correspondence. Correspondence from R. Hungerford to A.E. Verrill., 1887; 001249
    - Robert Hungerford Correspondence. A letter from Dr. R. Hungerford to A.E. Verrill informing him he is sending a "sort of worm or grub" which had been pulled from a 12 year old boy after it had "gnawed" its way to the surface of the skin near the boys groin. A note by Verrill on the letter reads " Parasitic larva? human"., 24 Feb 1887; 001250
  - Robert Tracy Jackson Correspondence. Correspondence from R.T. Jackson to A.E. Verrill., 1889; 001216
    - Robert Tracy Jackson Correspondence. A letter from R.T. Jackson to A.E. Verrill thanking him for the material and paper Verrill Had sent him. He also inquires of the availability of Pelycopoda specimens for his studies, offering to send material in exchange., 06 May 1889; 001217
  - Rudolf Leuckart Correspondence. Correspondence from R. Leuckart to A.E. Verrill., 1877; 001173
    - Rudolf Leuckart Correspondence. A letter from R. Leuckart to A.E. Verrill. The letter is in german., 15 Mar 1877; 001174
  - Rudolph Albert von Kolliker Correspondence. Correspondence from R.A. Kolliker to A.E. Verrill., 1867-1870; 001010